the rep fitness pr 1100 could this be
the best power rack for the money i mean
it is a power rack so it's got more to
offer than a squat rack it comes with
accessories that other brands make you
pay extra for
and compared to the rest of the market
it's incredibly cheap
[Music]
what's up y'all it's jake coming at you
live from the barbie garage gym and
today i've got the rep fitness pr 1100
in for review in this video i'm gonna
walk you through all the details of this
power rack the price some pros and cons
and most importantly who should and who
shouldn't buy it all right now before we
dive in i've reviewed a ton of squat
racks and power racks on barbin.com if
you want to explore more just head over
to google type in barbin best power
racks and find out where the pr 1100
wind up on that list
so let's talk about what i like about
this power rack well it features a
multi-grip pull-up bar that doesn't
always come standard with a power rack
at seven feet tall and four feet wide
you can put the pr 1100 almost anywhere
and with 14 gauge steel you can hold up
to 700 pounds on this power rack
oftentimes you'll find 11 gauge steel at
a professional gym but for the quality
of this 14 gauge and the price i think
this is a good option for a home gym
all right so here's some potential cons
that i could see with this power rack
while it does feature a small footprint
space is always a factor whenever you're
setting up your home gym so if you want
yours to be in your garage make sure
this thing will fit because if you're
parking in there you might need to look
at maybe just a traditional squat rack
or maybe even a foldable rack or one
that mounts on the wall secondly 700
pounds may be more than enough for you
but if you're one of those power lifters
that's really pumping the weight that
might not be enough you might want to
look at another option that can handle
more weight all right now let's dig into
the money here dollar dollar bills y'all
listed at under 400 on the rep fitness
website this includes a set of j-hooks
chrome safety arms and your pull-up bar
now you may be able to find cheaper
options online maybe at amazon but those
options may be of lesser quality and
feature fewer attachments speaking of
attachments the pr 1100 can be loaded
with them just head over to the rep
fitness website you'll find over 20
separate attachments you can add
directly to this rack anything from a
landmine attachment dip handles even a
lat row and pull down attachment and
since a power rack is the center piece
of your home gym
the original low price of this power
rack really allows you to expand and get
the most out of it
okay so let's dig into the build of this
power rack a little bit here as i
mentioned it's made with 14 gauge steel
but it also has a powder coat on it to
give it a nice matte black finish it's
seven feet tall and four feet wide the
depth of just under four feet and inside
the cage you're working with 44 by 45
and a half inches of working room plenty
of space to get a workout in and it is
worth mentioning that the spacing on
this power rack is not west side spacing
so west side spacing is one inch in
between each hole this is three inches
in between each hole so you might have
just a little bit of difficulty finding
that sweet spot to rack your barbell
all right so now it's time for the fun
part the attachments yes we mentioned
this power rack features a multi-grip
pull-up bar the j-hooks and the chrome
safety arms but also the beauty of it
you can add almost anything to it up to
20 different attachments so some of my
favorites are the dip handles the
landmine attachment and the lat row and
pull down attachment say you went with
the lat row pull down it also unlocks
the ability to do cable curls and you
can go and get an ankle cuff to work on
lower body movements such as kickbacks
but also if you want the landmine
attachment or the dip handles you also
need to accommodate for more space
because it will dominate more space the
dip handles stick out almost 20 inches
and with the landmine attachment you
have to make sure you have enough space
for the barbell to connect to it which
is almost another six feet
[Music]
all right so we're going to walk you
through some of the details now of the
pr 1100 as we mentioned this power rack
does not feature west side spacing so
you'll find there's a three inch gap in
between each hole which could
potentially lead to a little bit more
difficulty when you're finding that
sweet spot to rack your barbell let's
talk about my favorite feature now this
multi-grip pull-up bar
not only can you hit your regular
pull-ups
you can hit your close grip
and you can utilize this two-inch grip
back here but be sure to unbolt this
pull-up bar itself and flip it around or
else you might hit your head on the
frame
let's get into some of the safety
features now
these j-hooks are lined with the
strongest thermoplastic available on the
market ensuring that you do not harm
your barbell
or the frame itself when you're racking
it and also these chrome safety arms
right here
great safety feature in case you were to
drop your barbell for whatever reason
but try not to do that too often because
it could lead to some marks on your
barbell and you don't really want that
now if you were to add the landmine
attachment
that guy goes right in here just snap it
in there and you can put your barbell on
it unlock a whole another workout
and say you also wanted to do the dip
attachment right that guy attaches onto
here you find your height you want for
the safety arm attach the dip handles
and you're good to go and since this is
a movable power rack it definitely moves
as you can see there's a bit of a wobble
to it i noticed it in my time with it
but at the same time it was totally fine
i didn't feel as if it was a safety
hazard whatsoever but as you can see
there's a lot to like about this power
rack you can transform it add on
multiple attachments to it so they can
really be the centerpiece of your home
gym
[Music]
all right now you may ask me who should
buy the pr 1100 well if you're someone
who's looking for an affordable power
rack that offers durability and high
functionality you're gonna love this
rack also if you're looking for a power
rack that's fully customizable to meet
your needs you're gonna love the fact
you can put over 20 separate attachments
on this rack and third it features a
flat foot design meaning you don't have
to bolt it down if you don't want to it
also unlocks the ability to move it
around your gym as you please all right
now with all that being said there are
reasons why somebody may not want to
purchase the pr 1100 yes it does feature
a smaller footprint than some of its
competition but if you're tied on space
already you might want to look at a
foldable rack and plus when you add on
extra attachments it's going to demand
even more space than it already has this
power rack cannot be bolted into the
ground may be great for some people may
not be great for some people because it
does wobble a little bit if you're one
of those power lifters out there who
needs more than 700 pounds of weight the
pr 1100 is not for you my friend
unfortunately it cannot handle more
weight than that so you will need to
find another option that can alright
y'all that's all i got for you today on
the pr 1100 this is a cost efficient
power rack it's fully customizable to
fit your needs and become that true
centerpiece of your home gym it does
feature that multi-grip pull-up bar
which is a really nice touch because
not every power rack has that not to
mention the j-hooks and the chrome
safety arms for those added safety
measures so i really think this may be
the best power rack out there for the
money it does feature a relatively small
footprint but be sure to map out your
available space because some of these
attachments will demand more space and
increase your dimensions so to learn
more about this power act just search
barvin brett fitness pr 1100 and you can
read up on everything we discussed in
this video i hope i answered some
questions for you guys about the pr 1100
thanks for watching i'll see you next
time
[Music]
you